Guide to the Yale Diploma and Certificates Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale diploma and certificates collection
1920-1970
RU 366
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8.5
(6 boxes)
The material consists of blank samples of diplomas and certificates, press releases, and news clippings documenting degrees, certificates, and honors conferred by Yale.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 47 (YRG 47), Collections documenting teaching and learning in Yale academic programs.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The material consists of blank samples of diplomas and certificates, press releases, and news clippings documenting degrees, certificates, and honors conferred by Yale.
Diplomas
- Blank diplomas, Accession 19ND-A-400
  - Diplomas (Box 1–3)
- Blank diplomas and certificates, degree lists, and press releases, circa 1930-1970; Accession 1998-A-066
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Alcohol Studies (Box 1)
  - Bachelor of Arts (Box 1)
- Diploma collection as maintained by the Secretary's Office, Accession 2006-A-078
  - Architecture
    - Bachelor (Box 1)
    - Master (Box 1)
    - Conversion of the Bachelor to Master (Box 1)
  - Art
    - Master (Box 1)
    - Master Privatim (Box 1)
  - City Planning
    - Master (Box 1)
  - Divinity
  - Bachelor of Sacred Theology (Box 1)
    - Master of Sacred Theology (Box 1)
    - Doctor of Sacred Theology (Box 1)
    - Master of Arts in Religion (Box 1)
    - Master of Divinity..Conv. from Bachelor (Latin and English) (Box 1)
  - Master of Christian Education (Box 1)
  - Engineering (Box 1)
  - Bachelor (Box 1)
  - Master (Box 1)
  - Doctor (Box 1)
  - Fine Arts (Box 1)
    - Bachelor (Box 1)
    - Master (Box 1)
    - Doctor (Box 1)
  - Forestry
    - Master of Sylvan Science (Box 1)
    - Doctor (Box 1)
  - Honorary
    - Master of Art (Box 1)
    - Doctor of Law (Box 1)
    - Doctor of Letters (Box 1)
    - Doctor of Fine Arts (Box 1)
  - Industrial Administration
    - Master (Latin and English) (Box 1)
  - Law
    - Bachelor (Box 1)
    - Doctor of Law (Box 1)
    - Doctor of Civil Law (Box 1)
    - Doctor of Science Law (Box 1)
  - Letters
    - Doctor (Box 1)
  - Liberal Arts
    - Bachelor (Box 1)
    - Bachelor (varients) (Box 1)
  - Medicine
    - Doctor (Box 1)
    - Certificate of Residence (Box 1)
  - Nurse
    - Master (Box 1)
    - Master of Science in Nursing (Box 1)
    - Certificate in Nurse-Mid-wifery (Box 1)
  - Philosophy
    - Bachelor (Box 1)
    - Master (Box 1)
    - Doctor (Box 1)
    - Doctor (no Yale Date) (Box 1)
  - Public Health
    - Master (Box 1)
    - Doctor (Box 1)
    - Certificate, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Certificate, Undated (Box 1)
  - Science
    - Bachelors (English and Latin) (Box 1)
    - Master (Box 1)
  - Sheffield
    - Certificate of Completion (Box 1)
    - Certificate of Honor, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Certificate of Business Administration (Box 1)
    - Certificate of Withdrawal (Box 1)
  - Teaching
    - Master of Arts (Box 1)
  - Transportation
    - Certficate (Box 1)
  - Yale College
    - Bachelor of Arts Honor is Causa, 1918 (Box 1)
    - Certificate of Honor, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Credits for War Service (Box 1)
    - Blank..., 1924, 1925, 1929, 1931, 1942, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Certificate in Chinese Language (Box 1)
    - Certificate of Hospital Appointment (Box 1)
- Undergraduate and graduate diplomas and certificates of honor, circa 1920-1968; Accession 2007-A-057
  - Art
    - Master of Arts Privatim, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Master of Arts in Teaching (DocendiCausa), 1964 (Box 1)
  - Divinity
    - Master of Theology, Undated (Box 1)
  - Drama
    - Certificate (Male and Female), 1965 (Box 1)
  - Engineering
    - Doctor of Engineering, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Forestry
    - Master of Forestry (unsigned), 1944 (Box 1)
  - Honorary
    - Doctor of Laws
      - Seymour, 1950 (Box 1)
      - Beltran, 1960 (Box 1)
      - Pusey, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Law
    - Master of Laws, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Nursing
    - Master of Science in Nursing, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Sheffield
    - Certificate of Honor, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Urban Studies
    - Master of Urban Studies, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Yale College
    - Certificate of Honor, 1920 (Box 1)
    - Bachelor of Liberal Arts, Undated (Box 1)